面对学生们让人头疼的行为和学习问题，
旧金山的一所公立中学决定
尝试一些完全不同的东西。
这是他们的故事。
第一个词，第一部分。
First word, part one.
什么声音？
What sound?
E.
什么词？
What word?
纯的。
Pure.
好，下一个词，怎么发音？
Good, next word, what sound?
E.
这个是什么单词？
What word?
杰拉尔多？
Gerard?
你跟我们一起吗？
Are you with us?
什么单词？
What word?
学校。
School.
好吧，第二部分。
Okay, part two.
发什么音？
What sound?
♪ 第一声钵响，我讨厌这声音
♪ First bell rings I hate that sound.
♪ 低着头坐在教室后面
♪ Back of the class with my head down
♪ 要测验，压力山大
♪ Got a test,  all kinds of stress
♪ 不能再拿一个 F 回家
♪ Can't take home another F
呼吸的空间
♪ 有时我需要停下来
♪ Sometimes I need to stop
♪ 深呼吸
♪ And breathe
好了，该敲铃了。
Alright, time to ring the bell.
大家结伴而行。
Okay, partner up everybody.
我叫凌布什，
My name is Ling Busche,
是玛丽娜中学七年级的辅导员。
I'm a seventh grade counselor at Marina Middle School.
你得排到队伍最后。
You gotta go to the end of the line.
不错的尝试，德尚。
Nice try, Deshaun.
我们是规模较大的中学之一。
We're one of the larger middle schools.
我们的学生人数大约有九百。
We have a student population of about nine hundred.
今天排队很顺利。
Line is going pretty smooth today.
在学生人数方面，
There is a great divide
学校有很大的分化。
in terms of student population.
同学们，我们进去吧。
Guys, let's go inside.
我们已经有了荣誉班，
You've got the honors classes that
拥有表现最好的学生,
have the highest performing students,
他们没有行为方面的问题。
no behavior problems.
我们也有普通班，是个混合班级,
Then you have the general ed classes, which are a mix,
包括考试成绩最低的学生。
but contain students who have the lowest test scores.
我几乎没有收到荣誉班的行为转介报告。
I virtually get no behavioral referrals for the honors classes.
所有的学科转介
All of the disciplinary referrals
都来自于普通教育班。
are coming out of the general ed classes.
我们确实有看起来服务很好的学生，
We do haves students who seem well-served,
他们很成功，表现很好，
who are successful, who perform well and
而在同一个校园里，我们有一群学生
within our very same campus, we have a group of students who
与大家是完全脱节和脱离的。
are completely disconnected and disengaged.
在我们的学生中，有相当多的人
There is a significant number of our students
安东尼·布拉克森助理校长
不认为学校是一个适合他们待的地方。
that don't see school as a place for them.
我总是说，“他们不上学”
I always say it by saying, "they don't do school."
迭戈。
Diego.
一个捣乱的孩子会破坏
One disruptive kid can take away any learning
课堂上发生的任何学习。
that goes on in the class.
因此，其他孩子想捣蛋，
So other kids wanna misbehave
因为他们认为所有人都在捣蛋。
because they think everybody's misbehaving.
闭嘴，你这只蟋蟀。
Shut up, you cricket.
胖妈妈。
Fat mama.
哦。
Ooh.
当全班都疯了，都在扔铅笔时,
When the class is crazy, and throwing pencils,
它完全扰乱了我的注意力。
it messes up my concentration fully.
所以我就坐在椅子上什么都不做。
So the thing I do is I just sit in my chair and do nothing.
克里斯？
Chris?
转过身来学习。
Turn around, get on task.
我已经把更多的学生送出教室并停课了，
I have sent out and suspended from my classroom
这是我很长时间以来的第一次。
more students than I have in a long time.
你会给我惹麻烦的。
You're gonna get me in trouble.
我只是觉得这种行为完全是离经叛道，
I just find the behavior to be completely off the wall
汤姆 · 埃恩勒七年级教师
无法接受，不仅是对我，而且是对彼此。
and unacceptable, not just toward me, but toward each other.
很多孩子可能不会觉得
A lot of kids might not feel that
学校总是与他们息息相关。
school is always relevant to them.
学校是为特定类型的孩子设计的,
School is structured for a certain type of kid,
而他们可能不是那种类型的孩子。
and maybe they're not that type of kid.
这种情况达到了他们不觉得自己被听到的地步。
It reaches a point where they don't feel like they're heard.
十号到四十号，甚至...
Number ten to forty, even...
这是昨天的作业。
This was the assignment yesterday.
当你来到埃恩勒先生的课堂时,
When you visit Mister Ehnle's class,
感觉那里很混乱。
it feels very chaotic in there.
你们俩怎么了？
What is going on with you two?
拿出一张纸。
Get out a piece of paper.
科学。
Science.
有一种不停地娱乐的感觉，
There's sort of this sense of nonstop entertainment,
而课上发生的任何事情往往成为次要的。
and whatever's happening in the lesson often becomes secondary.
不要把两栖动物这个词拼错了。
Do not misspell the word amphibian.
总之,
Anyways,
我忘了我在说什么了。
I forgot what I was saying.
他们的参与是与
Their engagement is tied to
院子里发生的事情、
the drama that's happening in the yard,
脸书上发生的事情联系在一起的，
what's happening on Facebook,
他们被这些事情所吸引，
and they are consumed by it
所以在课堂上继续进行。
and so it just continues on in the classroom.
别踢我。
Stop kicking me.
你看到这头该死的鲸鱼刚刚做了什么吗？
Did you see what this freaking whale just did?
那是你的背包吗？
That's your backpack?
是的。
Yep.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
这是我的背包。
It's my backpack.
那是康纳的背包。
That's Connor's backpack.
珍妮特。
Jeanette.
珍妮特，离开教室!
Jeanette, leave the room.
我会和埃德温一起回去。
I'd go back out with Edwin.
坡度是M。
Slope is M.
我们取 Y 值。
We're going to take a Y value.
他在公交车上经常和蒂亚拉在一起，
He be hanging out with Tiara a lot on the bus,
总是和她坐在一起。
he always be sitting with her.
我知道，但他们闹掰了。
I know, but they broke up.
她和他闹掰了。
Well, she broke up with him.
对不起，如果我还是听到你们接头接耳，
Excuse me, if I continue to hear talking,
我就要给你们中一个或者两个换位子了。
one or both of you are gonna find a new seat.
呃。
Ugh.
不，不是“呃”。
No, that's not ugh.
而是，“是的， 埃德温先生”，然后续学习。
It's yes, Mister Ehnle, then you get on task.
教室里有那么多学生,
With that many bodies in a classroom,
当有人需要被转移到角落时,
when somebody needs to be moved off to a corner,
已经没有角落了，因为那里已经有人了。
there are no corners, 'cause there's already somebody there.
我已经放弃了。
I've given up.
我只是让他们坐到一起。
I just put 'em next to each other.
因为我宁愿让他们在彼此旁边说话、
'Cause I'd rather have them talking and yelling and
大喊大叫，而不是在教室里走来走去。
carrying on next to each other than across the room.
好好想想。
Think about it.
最近...
Lately...
如果没有人在接头接耳或分心，
We would all learn much more if nobody really
我们都会学得更多。
was talking or getting distracted.
我们都想提高成绩,
We would all, like, have our grades up,
我们都会是好孩子。
we would all be good kids and everything.
我知道我们是好孩子，都很聪明,
I know we're good kids, we're smart,
但有时候，我想我们太懒了，没有表现出来。
but sometimes, I guess we're too lazy to show it.
好的，你们有一分钟的时间来完成你的拼写，
Okay, you have one minute to finish your spelling
然后你们要拿出一本紫色的书，
and then you need to get a purple book
就摆在你们面前。
that's right in front of you.
你这个蠢货。
You stupid bitch.
这就是为什么没人喜欢你的丑屁股。
That's why nobody likes your ugly ass.
没人喜欢你。
No one likes you.
杰拉尔多，继续拼写。
Gerardo, keep going, you're doing it.
杰拉多有时会发火，
Gerardo does get angry sometimes
挑衅老师。
and seek out a challenge with his teachers.
他基本上只出现在课堂上，
He basically shows up and
而很少做作业。
produces very little work.
这确实让他的学习
It has really brought him down
成绩下降了。
in terms of his academic performance.
我不是唯一一个胡闹的人。
I'm not the only one that fools around.
是的，你是。
Yeah you are.
不，我不是。
No, I'm not.
闭嘴，我们会得到他妈的零分的。
Shut up, we're gonna get fucking zeroes.
如果我感到沮丧，就会躁动不安，然后,
If I get frustrated, I get hot and then after,
觉得死气沉沉，所有能量消失了。
I get cold, all the heat goes away.
我刚做完嘞所有的作业。
I just finished all my work.
我感觉不太好。
It's not a good feeling that I have.
你能不能不要在我的作业上写字？
Could you stop writing on my work?
好吗？
Please?
中学男生很难长时间
Middle school boys have trouble sitting still
坐着不动，在课桌前集中注意力。
for long periods of time and focusing at their desks.
一般来说这对他们不起作用,
This really doesn't work for them in general,
但这就是学校的情况。
but that's the way school looks.
这是学校的结构使然。
That's how it's structured.
请把书翻到第十五课。
Open your books, please, to lesson 15.
第一个词，是什么词？
First word, what word?
我已经读了。
I already did it.
奥马尔？
Omar?
奥马尔，当老师说读第一个单词的时候，
Omar, when the teacher says read the first word,
你就得这么做。
that's what you do.
我读了第一个单词。
I read the first word.
准备好了。
On cue.
埃恩勒先生的班级就像一个丛林。
Mister Ehnle's class is a jungle.
每天都有人被送出去。
Everyday somebody gets sent out.
教室里面总是很疯狂，每个人都离开了座位，到处乱跑。
Always it's wild in there, everybody's out of their seat, just around.
这让我很难集中注意力，因为我会分心。
It makes it hard for me to focus 'cause I get distracted.
这让我很难学习。
It makes it hard to learn.
我们重新学一遍。
So let's reconvene.
马利克？
Malik?
坐到杰奎琳旁边去。
Go sit over there by Jacqueline.
不。
No.
我真为这些不上进的
I really fear for these kids who
孩子们感到担心。
don't put forth the effort.
他们不努力。
They don't try.
他们没有坚持不懈。
They don't persevere.
下一个词。
Next word.
下一个词，怎么发音呢？
Next word, what sound?
什么单词？
What word?
很好，下一个词。
Good, next word.
怎么发音？
What sound?
如果你没有学会坚持，
How can you put together a relationship,
你怎么能投入到一段关系中，
how can you stay at a job when it's not fun
工作若无趣，你怎么还能干下去？
if you have not learned to persevere?
你到底怎么了？
What is it that you?
我看不进书。
I'm not reading.
你这样的行为是
You're not gonna help yourself be successful
不会帮助自己成功的。
when you're behaving like this.
奥马尔？
Omar?
什么？
What?
这不是帮助自己成功的方法。
This is not the way to help yourself be successful.
我确实喜欢学新东西,
I do like learning new stuff,
但如果老师们用一种我不理解的困难方式来教学，
but if they're teaching it in a difficult way that I don't understand,
那么我就不再努力了。
then I'm just gonna stop trying.
你知道吗？
You know what?
我不想听到任何争吵。
I don't wanna hear any arguing.
我知道我可以做得更好。
I know I could do better.
如果我只是交了作业。
If I just turned in my homework.
今晚的科学作业是十二点三分。
Tonight's homework for science is twelve dash three.
杰奎琳，坐到后面去。
Jacqueline, go sit in the back.
呃。
Ugh.
不，不要咂嘴，坐到后面去。
No, it's not smacking your lips, it's go sit in the back.
埃恩勒先生确实不尊重我。
Mister Ehnle does disrespect me.
他头上有个岛。
He has an island on his head.
穿得很奇怪。
He dresses weird.
戴着一副大眼镜。
He has huge glasses.
经常尖叫。
And he screams a lot.
不，你坐到杰拉尔多旁边。
No, you're next to Gerardo.
不，我坐到莱斯利旁边。
No, I'm next to Lesly.
你不仅在浪费自己的时间，
You're wasting not only your time,
可悲的是你在浪费别人的时间。
the sad part is you're wasting others' time.
我想知道这句话是什么。
I wanna know what the text is.
你打算什么时候再来一次？
When are you gonna have it again?
杰奎琳，如果你还在说话的话,
Jacqueline, if you are having a conversation,
要么结束它，要么到教室外去。
it will end or you will be out of the classroom.
你为什么总是把我赶出教室？
Why do you always send me out of the classroom?
啊？
Huh?
因为你话太多了。
Because you do so much talking.
他以为我总是
He's assuming that I'm always
那个挑起问题的人。
the one that's starting the problems.
这让我很生气。
It makes me feel mad.
杰奎琳，拿上你的东西，去见尼克。
Jacqueline, get your stuff and go see Nick.
当老师们在课堂上尝试了一些东西后，
When the teachers have tried things in the classroom,
学生就会被转诊。
then the student comes down with the referral.
当我们被赶出教室时,
When we get kicked out,
我们去学校办公室。
we go down to the office.
我总是被他赶出去的那个人。
I'm always the one that he sends out.
这感觉总是很糟。
It always feels bad.
有时，他们会因为以前的
Sometimes, they get pigeonholed because of,
行为模式而被归类。
you know, previous patterns of behavior.
我认为他们都觉得自己是弱者。
I think that they all feel like the underdogs.
没人支持他们。
No one's rooting for them.
杰拉尔多，当你被赶出去时,
Gerardo, when you get sent down,
十有八九是因为一些看起来
nine times out of ten it's because of something like,
很小的事情，比如说与人争吵。
which seems small, like an argument.
她好像觉得我以前做过这种事情，
She's like you have a history of doing stuff
我说，但我不会再做我以前的旧习了,
and I said but I'm not doing what I used to back,
这是六年级时的事情了
back in sixth grade or nothing.
进出办公室的学生很多,
A lot of the students that come in and out of the office,
讽刺的是，有时候感觉他们
ironically, sometimes it feels like they
想来咨询办公室,
want to come to the counseling office,
这有点进退两难，
which is a little bit of a dilemma
因为他们在教室外的时间更多。
because they're outside of the classroom more.
而这，有点，不公平。
And it's, like, not fair.
如果这一切都归结到它，
If it all boils down to it,
你搞砸了自己，因为...
you're messing yourself up, because...
但如果我什么都没做,
But if I'm not doing nothing,
我怎么搞砸了？
how am I messing myself up?
我怎么会，我怎么会，
How am I, how am I,
我不是什么都不做，
how am I the one that's putting myself into this
怎么会是我把自己扯进来的呢？
when I'm not doing nothing?
你要错过考试了,
You're missing your test,
现在让你补上那个测验，
so now it's gonna be kind of a hassle to get you
会有点麻烦的。
to make up that test.
集腋成裘。
It all adds up.
但我什么都没做。
But I didn't do anything.
没做什么？！
Nothing?！
什么都没做。
Nothing.
当你站在全班
When you're in the moment
同学面前的那一刻，事情就升温，
and you're in front of the class, things get heated,
他们就会...，问题就会升级。
they become, you know, the problem becomes escalated.
我想让我妈妈过来跟那位女士讲讲道理。
I want my mom to come and talk some sense into that lady.
好吧，她也可以参与其中。
Okay, well she can be part of that, too.
我发誓，她只是...
I swear, she just...
我们最近来了一位顾问，
We have a consultant that came in recently,
她居然把我们的学校说成是种族隔离的地方，
and she actually described our school as apartheid-land,
起初我有点反感，
which, I was at first a little bit offended by,
但想了想，我明白她的意思。
but after thinking about it, I understood what she meant.
因为她看到咨询办公室
Because she saw who was coming
里进进出出的学生。
in and out of the counseling office.
我不想看到你今天带着另一个推介来这里,
I don't want to see you in here with another referral today,
杰拉尔多.
Gerardo.
好吧。
Alright.
振作起来。
Get it together.
拉丁裔和非裔美国孩子
It's our Latino and African American kids
成绩不好，
who are underachieving,
他们不觉得自己是学校的一份子，
who don't feel like they're part of the school and
我们必须解决这个问题，
we have to address that,
我们必须让那些孩子成为学校的一部分，
we have to make those kids part of the school and
我们必须给那些学生机会，
we have to allow those students the opportunities and,
实际上，让他们可以更上层楼。
in fact, get them to achieve at a higher level.
嘿，克里斯，你为什么不来我的办公室，
Hey, Chris, why don't you just come into my office
我来帮你清理那张小桌子吧？
and I'm gonna clear off that little table for you?
一些让所有孩子受益的事情
Something that would benefit all of the kids
必须发生在所有的学生身上。
had to happen across all of the students.
所以当我们的一个治疗师
So when one of our therapists talked about the idea
谈到进入教室教授
of going into the classroom to teach
冥想策略以减少冲突、
meditative strategies which would reduce conflict,
集中注意力的想法时，我们就说，真是太棒了。
increase focus, you know, we were like, that's perfect.
莫伊塞斯？
Moises?
在。
Yes.
你怎么没去上课，伙计？
Why are you out of class, buddy?
我去买东西了。
I went to get groceries.
我们的停课率比这个城市的
We are suspending at a rate higher than
任何一所中学都要高。
any other middle school in this city.
我知道不能再这样下去了。
And I know that that has to stop.
我们想要做的是创造一种
What we'd like to do is create a sense of
这里是个社区的感觉，我们不会把人们赶出去的。
this is a community, and we're not just gonna push you out.
我们会帮助教你如何做，并做得很好。
We're gonna help teach you about how to do this and do it well.
所以我们要看看你在这个过程中的进展,
So we're gonna look and see where you are at in the process,
你经历过多少次这种事了。
how many times this has happened with you.
只发生过一次。
It's only happened once.
不过她说六年级的时候发生了意外。
She says there was a sixth grade incident, though, so.
我们之所以支持
So one of the reasons that we embraced bringing in
将正念引进课堂的原因之一是，
mindfulness into the classroom was to say
如果我们能在社区内创造一盏明灯，
a bright light within the community,
让成人和孩子们看到它们，
where adults and children can see that,
“嘿，有些东西真的在努力
hey, something is really working
让这个社区更具包容性，而且对每个人来说,
to make this community more inclusive and for everybody,
如果我们能开始在玛丽娜中学周围创造这个部分，
if we can start creating those spots around Marina Middle School,
那么其他人会看到它，并开始采取
then others will see it and start to adopt that
这种同理心和态度，说该学校
empathetic and that attitude of saying that the school
能满足更多的这些需求。
is gonna meet more of those needs.
我叫梅根·考恩，
My name is Megan Cowan,
来自一个叫正念学校的组织。
and I am here from an organization called Mindful Schools.
我们走进教室，
We go into classrooms
教授一种叫正念的东西。
and teach something called mindfulness.
我每周会去你们的教室两次，
I'm gonna be visiting your classroom twice a week
每次大概20或30分钟，
for just 20, maybe 30 minutes
我们在正念中要做的事情之一,
and one of the things that we'll be doing in mindfulness,
会有点不寻常,
which is gonna be a little bit unusual,
我想对你们中的一些人来说很奇怪，
and I think weird for some of you, is we're gonna,
我们会有一段时间是完全静默的。
there are gonna be periods of time that are totally silent.
那又怎样，我们要冥想吗？
So what, are we gonna be meditating?
如果你们有问题，请举手。
So let's raise your hand if you wanna have a question.
最大的误解是，
The biggest misconception is that
认为正念是灵性的或宗教的。
mindfulness is spiritual or religious.
虽然正念可以追溯到
Although it can be traced back to
梅根 · 库恩正念导师
非常传统的做法,
very traditional practices,
但它可以用世俗的方式来解决当今社会的问题。
it can be used in a secular way to address issues in society today.
我们现在要尝试的是
What we're gonna try right now is
我称之为正念的姿势。
just what I call mindful posture.
如果你们无精打采或者身体倾斜，
If you're slouching or leaning,
就暂时离开你们的椅子，
just lift off your chair momentarily for a few,
我们大概要做两分钟。
we're gonna do this for about two minutes, maybe.
请大家举起手，
And take your hands and
把它们放在桌上或腿上。
decide to put them either on your desk or in your lap.
你是说把手放在桌子上吗？
You said put them on your desk?
你也可以放在腿上。
Or in your lap.
然后注意你的身体是否有什么东西在动，
And then notice if anything in your body is moving,
比如你的腿在跳或者你的脚在动,
like if your leg is bouncing or your foot's moving,
或者你的手指在动。
or your fingers are moving.
我认为正念是一种工具或技能。
I think of mindfulness as a tool or a skill.
我们的社会和文化正在训练我们不要专注，
Society and our culture is training us to not be focused,
科技正在使我们一直不断地
so technology is causing us to jump from
从一件事跳转到另一件事上。
one thing to the next constantly, all the time.
当我们被要求或需要专注于某事时,
And when we're asked or required to focus on something,
我们的大脑实际上并没有准备好这样做。
our brain, actually, is not prepared to do that.
它没受过这方面的训练。
It's not trained to do that.
我认为在一个非常实用的层面上,
So I think on a very practical level,
正念在我们的生活创造了更多的聚焦点，
it's just creating more focus in our lives
并尽可能让一切变得宁静。
and try to let everything become still.
呃。
Ugh.
大家注意，这样很不舒服。
And notice that this is uncomfortable.
不过不是不舒服。
It's not uncomfortable.
如果你觉得有必要谈谈。
And if you feel the need to talk.
它真正教的是增加冲动控制，
It really teaches about increasing impulse control
这样我们在行动上就有了更多的选择。
so that we get more choice around our actions.
好了，现在放松。
Okay, now relax.
注意听我说。
Keep your attention with me.
我感觉糟透了。
I feel horrible.
是啊，告诉我你为什么不喜欢。
Yeah, tell me why you didn't like it.
感觉还不错。
It was like, it was alright.
后来，我感觉不到自己的身体，
Then later, I couldn't feel my body and
我的腿感觉有点怪怪的，
it felt kinda weird on my legs, so,
就像我中枪了或什么的，我不知道。
like if I got shot or something, I don't know.
大家可否往我这里看？
Can I have everybody's eyes up here?
谢谢你们。
Thank you.
克里斯？
Chris?
什么事，夫人？
Yes, ma'am?
在我离开之前,
Before I leave,
在我离开之前，我想告诉你们
before I leave, I wanna tell you guys about
正念背后的科学。
the science behind mindfulness.
科学表明，正念实际上会影响我们的大脑。
Science shows that mindfulness actually affects our brain.
当我们进行正念时,
And when we use mindfulness,
你们知道会发生什么吗？
you know what, you guys?
我们必须想出一些办法来让正念发挥作用，
We're gonna have to figure out some way to make this work
因为我要来15次。
since I'm gonna be here 15 times.
15次？
15 times?
我确实发现自己期望
I did find myself having expectations that I
在他们选择故意捣乱或在我离场
deserved some more time before they would choose to be
签出之前有更多的时间教授正念，
deliberately disruptive or before you check out,
但我认为冷漠是青少年的一部分,
but I think apathy is part of being a teenager,
所以我一点也不惊讶。
so I wasn't surprised.
所以我想问的是，
So what I wanna ask is that
在课堂上保持一定程度的注意力，
there's a certain level of attention in the class
表明你至少愿意听一会儿。
that shows that you are at least willing to listen for a while.
克里斯？
Chris?
如果你想要这种程度的注意力，
So, if you want this level of attention,
你得让事情变得有趣，
you gotta make stuff entertaining
因为这里的孩子都很好动。
'cause kids over here are hyperactive.
正念实际上是
Mindfulness actually is
训练你在不被外物娱乐的
training you to be comfortable
时候感到舒适自在。
when you're not being entertained.
因为在你的一生中，
'Cause you will not be entertained
你不会一天24小时都得到娱乐。
24 hours a day of your whole life.
等一下。
Hang on.
梅根进来的时候，我想，哦，伙计，
When Megan came in, I thought, oh man,
我们这么糟糕，他们还要把我们拍成电视节目？
we're that bad they gotta bring a T.V. show about us?
我不知道我们班是怎么被选中的，
I'm not sure how our class was chosen,
但是...
but...
孩子们问为什么要把正念课程带到他们的教室，
The kids ask why mindfulness was brought to their classrooms
因为其他教室并没有提供正念课程，
because it's not being offered in other classrooms,
我想他们知道其原因为何。
and I think they know the reason why.
一般来说，这个课程有时候会让人有点抓狂。
Generally, that the classes are a little bit crazy at times.
当他们如此习惯于走另一条路，
It's hard to go down that road when they're so used to
即混乱和无序的路时，
going down the other road
很难走有序这条路。
which is a road of chaos and disorder.
如果他们合作,
If they cooperate,
而且他们，如果留心的话，他们会改变，但是，
and they, like, pay attention, they would change but
不过我知道有些孩子不会合作,
because I know some of the kids won't,
我不知道这个班的情况。
I don't know about the class.
他们进去了吗？
Did they get in?
莱斯利,
Lesly,
她上课不认真听讲。
she doesn't pay attention in class.
她没有完成她应该做的家庭作业。
She doesn't do homework like she should.
这不是我的错。
It's not my fault.
因为你没告诉我作业在哪儿！
because you didn't tell me where it is!
以前，她总是注意听讲，
Before, she always paid attention,
上交作业，
turned in her work
老师们从不抱怨。
the teachers never complained.
并不是我所有的家人
Not all of my family members
都完成了初中和高中的学业,
got to finish middle school and high school,
我想向他们证明，我可以做
and I want to show them that I can do
他们已做过的事情，我想向他们证明，
what they could have done, and I want to prove to them that
我可以去上大学，让他们看看，
I can go to college and show them that
我找到了一份好工作，并改变了我的生活。
I'm getting a good career and changing my life.
我们要祈祷。
We're going to pray.
我们总是和她说话。
We always talk to her.
尽量不要在课堂上说话。
So, try to limit conversation in class.
课堂是为了学习，大家要注意听讲，
The class is for studying, paying attention,
友谊是留给你离开学校的时候的。
friendships are for when you leave school.
我告诉你该做什么，你却不听。
I tell you the things you should do, but you don't listen.
我去教堂，祈祷你能打开心扉，
I go to church and pray for you to open your mind
在学校表现好，做正确的事，
do good in school, do things right
不要做坏事。
for you not to do bad things.
当我看到她情况不好，
When I see that she's not doing well
我告诉她这里没有电话,
I tell her there's no telephone,
没有电视，
there's no television
不能购物，去不了商店，
there's no shopping, going to the stores
或者如果你想要什么，我会告诉她什么都没有，
or if you want something, I tell her there's nothing
因为如果你表现糟糕，
because if you don't behave
我不会给你奖品的。
I'm not going to give you a prize.
如果你不付出努力，
If you don't put forth effort
谁来养活你，让你活下去？
who is going to give you a living so you can live?
没人，对吧？
Nobody, right?
有时候我告诉她，你拥有
Sometimes I tell her, you've got everything
像我这样的人在自己的国家所没有的一切。
that a person like me doesn't have in their own country.
而你却不知道如何利用这一点。
And you don't know how to take advantage of it.
这让我很难过。
That makes me sad.
对我来说，作为一个母亲，
For me, as a mother
这是最悲哀的事情，这么多年轻人
that's the saddest thing, that so many young
是拉丁裔父母的孩子，
people that are the children of Latino parents
他们在这个国家出生，
kids who've been born in this country
却没有完成学业。
and they don't finish school.
当钵声完全消失的时候,
When the sound of the bell is completely gone for you,
请大家举手。
raise your hand.
当梅根第一次来到这个班级时，
When Megan first came to the class,
我们真的不知道发生了什么。
we really didn't know what was going on.
我们通常很吵，在房间里大喊大叫，
We're usually loud and we yell across the room and
我们会从座位上站起来,
we just get up from our seats and like,
开开玩笑什么的。
crack jokes and stuff.
当她来到教室时，我们只是不想在课堂上
We were just trying not to be our normal selves in class
做正常的自己，但是有点困难。
when she came in, but it was kinda hard.
你能转过来吗？
Can you turn this way?
把你的椅子转过来，
Just go ahead and turn your whole chair
面朝前面。
and face that way.
再往前挪挪，
And go ahead and scoot up like,
一英尺半左右。
a foot and a half.
谢谢，要面朝前面。
Thanks, but facing that way.
把椅子转过来，
Like, just turn your chair
这样你正面朝向前面。
so you're exactly facing that way.
谢谢。
Thanks.
我是面朝那边的。
I am facing that way.
好的，但你明白我为什么这么问吗？
Okay, but do you understand why I'm asking?
是的。
Yes.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
请大家把手放在肚子上，
So put your hand on your belly
每个人都深呼吸一次，
and everybody take one deep breath
只有你自己能听见。
that only you can hear.
我们再试一次。
Let's try it again.
现在,
And now,
请做五次轻柔呼吸,
take five gentle breaths,
注意在腹部是否有感觉。
noticing if you feel it in your belly.
大家把手放在肚子上，这给了你另一种
You have your hand on your belly, it gives you another
感受自己真正在呼吸的方式。
way to feel that you actually are breathing.
呼吸对我们的情绪是有反应的,
Our breathing is responsive to our emotions,
所以这是一个与你的经验保持联结的好方法,
so it's a nice way to stay connected with your experience,
那就是观察或注意你的呼吸。
is to be watching or noticing your breathing.
接着我们做三次呼吸，
And then take three breaths,
注意你是否在胸部感觉到它。
noticing if you feel it in your chest.
梅根刚来
When Megan first came
教第一堂正念课时，
to teach the first mindfulness class,
我想离开教室。
I was like get outta here.
我不想做正念练习，你知道吗？
I don't wanna do this, you know?
我一开始也想表现得像个好孩子,
I was trying to look like a good kid in the beginning, too,
不过扔铅笔什么的也挺有意思的。
but then it was fun throwing pencils and stuff, you know.
不听老师的话总是很有趣,
Not listening to teachers is always fun,
但我知道这不是该做的事。
but it's not the thing to do.
我们要做一个挑战，
We're gonna do a challenge,
这个挑战就是正念呼吸一分钟。
and the challenge is to do mindful breathing for a minute.
每个人都要保持正念的姿势。
So everybody in your mindful posture.
什么？
What?
椅子。
Chair.
不，不，不，不，不，不。
No, no, no, no, no, no.
不是“不”。
It's not no.
不，不，不，不，不。
No, no, no, no, no.
我不想过去。
I don't want to go over there.
我没问你想不想。
I didn't ask if you wanted to.
是的，你说了。
Yes, you did.
我知道有些事让你分心了,
So, I know there's some distraction,
但我们还是要继续。
but we're just gonna continue.
从现在开始，我们要做一分钟的正念呼吸。
We're gonna do a minute of mindful breathing starting now.
克里斯，你能把手放进去吗？
Chris, can you put your hand in?
我要走过去。
I'm gonna walk by.
克里斯？
Chris?
谢谢你。
Thank you.
对于你们中的一些人来说，
For some of you, there was something about that experience
这种经历可让人感到愉快或者正面。
that may have felt pleasant, or positive.
嘿，伙计们？
Hey, guys?
你叫什么来着？
What's your name again?
拉斯蒂·沙克尔福德。
Rusty Shackleford.
马特 · 拉斯蒂 · 沙克尔福德,
So Matt Rusty Shackleford,
你能不能把注意力集中在上面？
can you help me out by just having your attention up here?
好吧。
Alright.
好的。
Okay.
我想邀请四五个同学
So can I hear from four or five people
用一个词能形容一下你刚才的感受？
one word that describes what that was like for you?
冷静。
Calm.
冷静？
Calm?
你认为这是一个
And would you describe that as
愉快的还是不愉快的经历？
a pleasant or unpleasant experience?
愉快的。
Pleasant.
谢谢你的分享。
Thank you for sharing.
莫妮卡，你到外面去。
Monica, go outside.
你真的太干扰大家了。
You do too much, for real.
我知道你不喜欢期望。
I know you don't like expectations.
我喜欢，但我不喜欢你的。
I do, but I don't like yours.
这并不是说很难达到他们的要求，
It's not like it's hard to reach them,
只是他们表现得好像
it's just like they wanna act
他们并不真正关心什么似的。
like they don't really care about nothing.
但我知道他们在乎。
But I know that they do care.
他们想表现得很强硬。
They're trying to act like they're tough.
当他们真的没有比那更好的时候，
They try to act like, oh, I'm better than this, you know,
他们试图表现得好像，哦，我可以更好。
when they're really not better than that.
关于一分钟的正念呼吸，
Raise your hand if something about
如果有什么不愉快的感觉的同学，请举手。
a minute of mindful breathing was unpleasant.
我不习惯如此安静的呼吸。
I'm not used to breathing so quiet.
我在旧金山住了很久,
I've lived in San Francisco for a long time,
所以总能听到汽车之类的声音。
so you always hear like cars and stuff.
而且声音不吵，所以。
And it wasn't noisy, so.
好吧，你已经习惯旧金山的噪音了。
Okay, so you're used to the noise in San Francisco.
我们现在要用钵声结束今天的课程。
So we're gonna end right now with the bell.
嘘。
Ssh.
我们做了正念呼吸,
We did do mindful breathing,
所以我完成了我的意图,
and so I accomplished what the intention was,
但是我觉得这个班级并没有真正理解。
but it didn't feel like the class really got it.
这次课总共花了35分钟。
And it took 35 minutes.
真的想找到一种方法来触达他们，
You just really want to find a way to reach them and
但没找到，所以我不知道,
you're not, and so I don't know,
我不知道下一步该怎么做。
I don't know where to go next with it.
嘿，那是马利克。
Hey, there's Malik.
他们绕过拐角。
They go around the corner.
史蒂文 · 霍普金斯和我一起上课后班。
Steven Hopkins goes to After School with me.
这样我们才能远离麻烦。
That's how we stay out of trouble.
学期开始时，我的成绩都是 A。
In the beginning, I had like, all As.
在学期中间，我开始不想
And during the middle I just started not wanting to
做作业了。
do my work and stuff.
我只是去学校，甚至什么都不做，
I would just go to school and not even do anything,
不做什么作业，就去玩。
just not do my work, go have fun.
你想做什么？
What do you want to do?
不做什么。
Yeah, nothing.
很好。
That's good.
不过有点快。
Kind of fast though.
是吗？
Does it?
是的。
Yeah.
每次他回家，我都会问他你还好吗？
When he comes home, I always ask him are you okay?
学校怎么样，你做了什么？
How was school, what did you did?
有什么变化吗，有什么问题吗？
Anything change, anything wrong?
我试图至少了解
So I try to get at least an idea of what happens
他一天中发生的事情。
during the day for him.
如果我只是把他晾在一边，从不和他说话，
If I just put him on the side and never talk to him,
或者不关心他做了什么,
or don't care about what he does,
那就不一样了。
then that's different.
是的。
Yeah.
杰拉尔多现在有麻烦了。
Gerardo is in trouble now.
在过去也许，我会说在一年或一年半的时间里,
For the past maybe, I would say a year, year and a half,
我们和他之间存在很大的问题。
we're having really hard issues with him.
上学迟到。
Tardiness.
出勤率低。
Attendance.
行为表现差。
Behavior.
他交的朋友，他做的事都有问题。
The friends that he hands with and the things that he does.
就好像如果你做得好，他们就会给你加分。
It's like if you're doing good, they give you pluses.
如果你在外面鬼混，或者不在座位上什么的,
If you're fooling around or not in your seat or something,
他们就会给你减分。
they give you circles.
你今天得了多少 “+” ？
How many pluses you got today?
总数还是在小组里。
Altogether or in the group.
共八个。
Eight.
在你们十号组呢？
In your group, in table ten?
- 有八个“好”?              - 是的。
- Eight good?                - Yeah.
“差”有几个？
How many bad?
七个。
Seven.
我们在做加减计算吗？
Are we doing equal here?
最后的表现是负数还是正数？
Are we doing minus or plus?
来吧。
Come on.
有时候会有人推介我,
And I was getting referrals sometimes,
一天五次推介，还有他做的事,
five referrals a day, and the thing with him,
他喜欢顶嘴。
he likes to talk back.
有一次我上班的时候，学校打电话给我说：
One time they called me at work and says,
“你得马上来接杰拉尔多。
you have to come pick up Gerardo right now.
我们不能再让他留在学校了”。
We cannot keep him in school no more.
我说，现在是早上11点。
And I'm like, it's 11 in the morning.
他说，你得来接他。
He says well, you need to come pick him up.
他们巴不得你离开这个地方，不要再回来了。
They just want you to leave the premise and don't come back.
这是很糟糕的。
That is pretty bad.
但我当时做得很好。
But I was doing good, though.
我明白，但要多久？
I understand, but for how long?
我毕业于玛丽娜中学。
I graduated from Marina Middle School.
我和杰拉尔多一模一样。
I was exactly like Gerardo.
我很聪明。
I was very smart.
实际上，我曾是六个月的月度最佳学生，
I was actually the student of the month for six months.
我有大约六个月的荣誉榜。
I had honor roll for about six months.
然后一切都变糟了。
And then everything went down sour, too.
我开始和不三不四的人混在一起,
I started hanging with the wrong crowd,
答非所问，不做作业,
answering back, not doing homework,
直到最后我被学校开除。
until eventually I got kicked out of school.
有时候我在课堂上胡闹。
Sometimes I fool around in class.
哦，这我知道，你不用告诉我。
Oh, that I know, you don't have to tell me.
你认为你为什么坐在前面？
Why do you think you sit in the front?
因为你很特别？
'Cause you're special?
因为我爱我的老师。
'Cause I love my teacher.
不，你不爱。
No, you don't.
好吧。
Alright.
不，有关系。
No, it's not alright.
别只告诉我好吧，别只告诉我要安静,
Don't just tell me alright just to tell me to be quiet,
我只想表达我的观点。
I'm trying to make a point here.
对我来说按时上班是不公平的，
It would not be fair for me to go to work on time
当每次我准时上班时，其他人都迟到。
and have everybody else be late when I'm on time every time.
我知道我的工作是什么，
I know what my job is,
我不需要有人来告诉我我要做什么工作。
I don't need someone to come tell me you need to do your job.
是的。
Yeah.
有一些小事情，我很后悔我做了，
There's little things out there that I regret I done
而我，相信，我若可以回去，我会改变它的。
and I was, believe, I coulda go back, I woulda change it.
这就是我想教他的,
That's the thing that I'm trying to teach him,
我说，我可以做你的镜子，看看我在哪里。
I says look at my mirror, look where I am.
看看我都经历了什么。
Look what I gone through.
我一直在洗碗，我一直在做门卫工作,
I been doing dishes, I been doing janitorial work,
我做过各种各样的工作。
I been doing all kind of jobs.
我一直在街上卖水果,
I've been selling fruits in the street,
对我来说，这不是什么新鲜事，但对他来说,
so to me, that's nothing new, but for him,
他有机会和可能性成为这里的一员,
that he has the chance and the opportunity to be somebody here,
他只是没有利用这一点,
he just doesn't take advantage of it,
我觉得这是浪费时间。
I think it's a waste of time.
我不认为学校...
I don't think the school...
但他需要想出更好的选择。
but he needs to come up with better choices, though.
对吧？
Right?
是的。
Yeah.
听起来好像我们在香港。
Sound like we're in Hong Kong.
大家注意了。
Can I have your attention.
周一的事,
So the way things went on Monday,
对正念来说是行不通的，所以我需要找出
it's not gonna work for mindfulness, so I need to find out
谁真的不想在这里参加正念。
who really does not want to be here for mindfulness.
如果你不想待在这里，
I'm gonna need each of you that are raising your hand
你们可以举手示意，并告诉我为什么。
that you don't want to be here, to tell me why.
所以你不想来是因为？
So you don't want to be here because?
很无聊吗？
It's boring?
又无聊又愚蠢。
It's boring and it's stupid.
你有没有发现你生命中有什么东西是无聊或愚蠢的？
Do you ever find other things in your life boring or stupid?
没有。
No.
没有，从来没有？
No, never?
所以这是唯一的喽？
So this is the only thing?
你真的想出去吗？
So you definitely wanna go?
是的。
Yeah.
好的。
Okay.
有几个孩子
There are a few kids
对班上其他人特别有挑战性。
who make the rest of the class particularly challenging.
如果他们中的五个人不在教室里，
If there were five of them that weren't in there,
那么其他大多数同学实际上就会尝试，
then the majority of them actually would be trying
也会参与到正念课程中。
and would be participating.
迭戈，过来。
Diego, come here.
站起来。
And stand up.
请走到这里来。
Just come all the way over here.
好了，他们和你们一起出去。
Okay, they're just gonna head outside with you guys.
我们将在你们不在的情况下上课。
And we're gonna have the class without you.
谢谢你。
Thank you.
作为一个项目，我们的理念是
It's our philosophy as a program that
所有学生都要在课堂上，
all students are present in the class,
即使他们是捣蛋鬼，
even if they are the disruptive ones,
因为我们相信他们甚至
because we believe that they are the ones
可能是获得最大利益的人。
that might even gain the most benefit.
但是，现在我所看到的是，
But, right now what I'm seeing is
有几个孩子造成了如此多的破坏，
there's a handful of kids that are causing so much disruption,
以至于牺牲了班上其他30个孩子的利益。
that it's at the expense of the other 30 kids in the class.
30个孩子正在等着班上所有同学都安静下来。
30 kids are waiting for the class to settle down.
如果你现在要参加这个课程,
If you're participating in the class,
请把椅子转向前方。
please turn your chairs this way.
大家往这里看。
Everybody's eyes up here.
克里斯？
Chris?
当我在结束时环顾四周，有一个男孩如此
It really did strike me when I looked around at the end
专注地看着我，这确实让我印象深刻，
and there was one boy just looking at me so intently,
然后我环顾四周，我意识到，
and then I looked around and I realized,
好吧，有一半的人只是在等待
well, a good half of the class is just waiting
班上其他的人振作起来。
for the rest of the class to get it together.
一些已经准备好并愿意做的人
Some of the people that are ready and willing to do it
会感到不舒服，
are not gonna feel comfortable
除非班上其他同学都安顿好了。
unless the rest of the class is settled in.
你为什么不问问这里所有的孩子
So why don't you ask all the kids in here
他们现在感觉舒服吗？
if they're feeling comfortable right now?
这是我一直想进行的对谈。
That's a conversation that I've been trying to have.
所以当钵声消失的时候请举手。
So raise your hand when the sound of the bell is gone.
哦，我们本来要去吃午饭的。
Oh, we're supposed to be going to lunch.
就像头撞南墙。
It's like hitting a brick wall.
我很沮丧，有点无可奈何。
I just am frustrated and kind of hopeless.
反抗是如此的刻意，
The defiance is so deliberate and
我不知道我是否能在这么大的
I don't know if I can work with that
一个团体中解决这个问题。
in this large of a group.
因此，我和布拉克斯顿先生和布什小姐坐下来，
So, I sat down with Mister Braxton and Miss Busche to ask
商议我该如何回应这堂课。
how I should respond to this class.
我在这些孩子身上特别遇到的问题是，
The problem that I'm meeting with these kids in particular is
有四个孩子在故意捣乱，
that four kids are being deliberately disruptive
牺牲了其他30个学生的利益。
at the expense of 30 other students.
我们是一所公立学校。
We're a public school.
我们因材施教每位学生，
We take everybody where they're at
并尽我们所能为他们做最好的工作，
and we do the best job we can with them
那种认为30个孩子在等5个孩子的想法...
and the idea that 30 kids are waiting for five kids...
是的。
Yeah.
或者认为这些孩子是受害者，
Or that somehow these kids are the victims
或者认为他们不会以牺牲别人为代价来获得某些东西,
or they're not getting something at the expense of others,
这是我不想建立的模式,
that's a paradigm I prefer not to set up,
即有些人有收获，而有些人没有，
that some get and some don't
牺牲五个学生的利益以便让其他人有收获。
and that we sacrifice five so that others do.
我们应该给每个学生同样的东西。
We should give the same thing to everybody.
不过，它可能不会以同样的方式出现。
It may not come in the same way, though.
我对此并不介意。
And I'm okay with that.
我们一天一天慢慢来。
Let's take this one day at a time.
今天我们要带他们四个出去上课。
And today we'll take those four out for the class.
你会有一些时间和他们在一起，
You'll have some time with them and then maybe
然后你我也许可在我今天离开之前联系一下，
you and I can touch base before I leave today
听听他们的谈话情况如何。
just to hear how that conversation went.
然后当班级作为一个整体回来时，
And then reintegrating them when
再把他们重新整合起来，
that class comes back together as a whole,
这对班上的四个孩子来说并不陌生。
it's not foreign to four kids in the class.
对的。
Right.
我开过一次家长会，情况很糟糕，
I had a parent teacher conference and it was bad,
因为老师们都在说我的坏话。
'cause the teachers were talking bad about me.
根本不做作业。
Not a lick of work.
数学作业，科学作业，什么都没上交,
Nothing turned in, math or science.
我总是在挂墙投影仪上这么做。
I always do this on the overhead projector.
通过不做作业,
By not doing homework,
她觉得这样才能报复老师。
she thinks that's the way she can get back at the teacher.
每天，她都应该能带
Everyday, she should be able to bring
一份像这样的文件回家。
a paper home that looks like this.
这是我们今天在数学课上教的内容。
This is what we did in math class today.
她数学落后了，
She got behind in math and
阅读和写作也落后了,
reading and writing, also,
因为老师把她送到了办公室。
because the teacher sent her to the office.
我们连续三天都在谈论这个问题。
We talked about it for three days in a row.
当我去学校时，
When I went to school,
完成家庭作业需要两三个小时，完成后，
homework means like two, three hours and then
我就有自由时间了。
I have my free time.
我，林恩和莱斯利 · 马丁内斯一起做的。
Me, Lyn and Lesly Martinez worked on it.
在美国，他们觉得很无聊。
In America, it's like, boring for them.
拿不拿到毕业证书，随便了。
Getting a diploma is like, whatever.
那会得到什么呢？
What is that going to get?
你真的不该觉得这很糟糕。
You really shouldn't even think that's bad.
你会为自己感到骄傲的。
You're gonna be so proud of yourself.
校长说如果她再犯错误的话，
The Principal said that if she gets one more thing,
她就得换个学校。
she'll have to change the school.
但我不想让她离开玛丽娜学校。
But I don't want her to get out of Marina.
我喜欢这所学校。
I like the school.
她可以表现得很好，
She could do very well
如果她集中精力，真的决定
if she focused and really decided
要成为一个优秀学生的话。
I'm gonna be a great student.
我想我必须改变我的整个态度，
I think I would have to change my whole attitude
开始好好学习，
and start doing my work
并完成作业。
and my homework.
所有的家庭作业。
All of my homework.
我想这真的取决于你。
I think it's really up to you.
我觉得你有足够的能力，
I think you have the resources and
只需要你决定做好你的那部分。
it just takes a decision on your part to do your part.
我希望能通过考试。
I hope to pass.
我有点难过。
I would feel kind of sad.
如果我不及格，
If I don't pass,
就不能和我的朋友们继续交往了。
then I don't get to go on with my friends and move on.
来学校整整一年，如果最后没有毕业，
Doesn't make any sense, to come to school for the full year
那就说不通了。
if at the end, you don't graduate.
我在浪费时间。
I waste my time.
我认为这是个警钟。
I did think that was a wake up call.
我离开学校时想着要好好学习，
I walked out thinking start doing good,
别再被老师点名批评了，开始做家庭作业和课堂作业。
stop getting referrals and start doing my homework and classwork.
当我早上醒来,
When I wake up in the morning,
想到今天是要去学校教书,
and it's the day that we're teaching at this school,
我心中就有一种轻微的恐惧，
I have a mixture of mild dread
也有一些关于我今天能做什么的决定。
and also some determination of what can I do today?
这些课程一直在我脑海里。
These classes are on my mind all the time.
当我觉得自己无法触及这些学生时,
When I feel like I'm not reaching them,
我觉得这是不可接受的，所以我想
that's not acceptable so I wanna get creative
发挥创造力并想办法触及他们。
and figure out how to reach 'em.
好吧。
Okay.
我打算让你们来引导正念。
I'm gonna have you guys start leading mindfulness.
请闭上眼睛。
Please let your eyes close.
我本来不打算今天在课堂上尝试正念，但我还是试了。
I wasn't planning to give it a try today in class but I kinda did.
好的，谢谢。
Okay, thank you.
好了，伙计们。
Alright, you guys.
你认为你生活中什么对你有最大影响？
What do you think is your biggest influence in your life?
每个人都开始提高注意力，
Everybody started paying attention
这与其他课程不同。
and it was different from the other classes.
莱斯利，你的答案是？
Lesly?
爸爸。
Dad.
杰奎琳，你呢？
Jacqueline?
我姐姐。
My sister.
好的，我们有人说了爸爸和姐姐。
Okay, so we've got dad, sister.
杰拉尔多，你呢？
Gerardo?
艺术。
Art.
如果我告诉你，你生命中对你有
Would you be surprised if I told you
最大影响的是你的心智，你会感到惊讶吗？
the biggest influence in your life is your mind?
当我们练习正念时，
And when we practice mindfulness,
你正在加强你的心智，
you're strengthening your mind
让它对你的生活产生你想要的影响。
to have the influence  on your life that you want it to have.
当我们练习正念呼吸时,
And when we practice mindful breathing,
我们正在发展心智的力量，
we're developing the strength of our mind
以便对我们产生影响。
to have influence on us.
我很难坐着不动，
It was hard to sit still
很难不动手或任何东西。
and to not move my hands or anything.
这就像，好吧，我只需要冷静下来，
It was just like, okay, I just need to calm down and
告诉自己不要动，看看这样行不行。
tell myself to stop moving to see if this works or not.
我们可以用想法在我们的生活中
One way that we can create influence in our life
产生影响的一种方式是聚焦意图，
with our mind is by having thoughts on purpose,
而不是胡思乱想。
rather than thoughts on accident.
因此，继续前进，回到一个正念的体态。
So go ahead and get back into a mindful position.
我要说一句话。
I'm gonna say a phrase.
我想让你们在心里默默地重复念的一句话是：
So the first thing I want you to repeat, silently in your mind, is
我祝自己快乐。
I wish for myself to be happy.
然后试试这个愿望，我祝自己健康。
And then try the wish, I wish for myself to be healthy.
现在在你的脑海中创造一个针对你自己的愿望，
And now create a wish in your mind that is specific to yourself,
无论是你想要完成的事情，
whether it's something you want to accomplish,
还是你想要拥有的品质，
a quality that you want to have,
还是你想要做的事情。
something you want to do.
我为自己许愿,
I wish for myself,
你们来填空。
you fill in the blank.
它只是帮助你放松，忘记其他的事情。
It just helps you relax and forget about everything else.
有没有人愿意说说
Is anyone willing to say
为自己许下了什么愿望？
what they wished for themselves?
是的，你对自己许了什么愿望？
Yes, what was your wish for yourself?
更轻松惬意的生活。
An easier life.
谢谢。
Thank you.
杰拉尔多，你呢？
Gerardo?
在学校表现更好。
To do better in school.
太好了。
Great.
在他的课上表现更好。
In his class.
谢谢。
Thank you.
你希望在学校表现得更好,
You wish to do better in school,
尤其是埃恩勒先生的课上。
particularly Mister Ehnle's class.
是的。
Yeah.
我想搬到阿拉斯加。
I want to move to Alaska.
你想搬到阿拉斯加？
You wish to move to Alaska?
是的。
Yeah.
好的，太好了，谢谢。
Okay, great, thank you.
如果这是你第一次对
Raise your hand if this was the first time that you
幸福有了目的性的想法，请举手。
had thoughts on purpose about your happiness.
好的。
Okay.
今天我想让你们祝自己幸福三次。
I want you, three times today, wish yourself happiness.
好吗？
Okay?
但你们的挑战是要记住做这件事。
But your challenge is to remember to do it.
我想对你们今天的参与
And I want to express my deep appreciation
表示深深的感谢。
for your participation today.
今天的课确实让我感到更有希望，
Today's class definitely does make me feel more hopeful
我们会在这门课上有所收获。
that we're gonna get somewhere in this class.
今天那间教室真的发生了变化，
That room really shifted today and I felt like
我感觉学生们真的以一种对他们有帮助的
the students really participated in a way that
方式参与进来，对每个人都有帮助，
was helpful to them, as in each individual,
对整个教室也有帮助。
but also as a classroom.
好的，谢谢。
Okay, thanks.
谢谢你 ，埃恩勒先生。
Thank you, Mister Ehnle.
我对正念课程有些想法。
I have thoughts about the mindfulness program.
我非常愿意参与，
I'm perfectly willing to participate and
我希望它能帮助学生学习，
I hope it helps students in learning
并有效地利用
and effectively using the opportunity
他们在中学经历的这个机会。
that is their middle school experience.
六，七，八。
Six, seven, eight.
早上好。
Good morning, again.
嗨。
Hi.
早上好。
Good morning.
近来可好？
How are you?
很好。
Good.
我们要进入正念的倾听。
We're gonna go into mindful listening.
当尝试一些你可能以前没有做过的事情时，
I encourage you to have an open mind this morning,
我鼓励你们今天早上有一个开放的心态。
while we try something that you probably haven't done before.
把你的注意力放在声音上，
Keeping your attention on sound,
听房间外面的声音。
listen to the sounds outside the room.
然后专注于你内心的声音。
And then focus on the sounds inside of you.
一开始，因为她的穿着，
At first, well, I thought she was like a voodoo person,
我以为她是个巫毒教徒。
'cause of what she was wearing.
你们真的很正念。
You guys got really mindful.
你能确定你听外面的
Can you identify how you felt
声音有什么感觉吗？
listening to the sounds outside?
我有点不耐烦。
I was a little impatient.
有点不耐烦？
A little impatient?
是的。
Yeah.
是啊，怎么了？
Yeah, why?
因为我习惯了动来动去和接头接耳。
'Cause I'm used to  and chatting a lot.
没错，你们习惯了动来动去和接头接耳，
You're used to moving and chatting, exactly.
所以尽量正念倾听声音,
So try to be mindful of sounds,
外在的、内在的，你自己内心的声音。
outside, inside, inside yourself.
我们周一见。
And I will see you on Monday.
再次感谢你们，你们太棒了。
Thank you again, you guys, that was great.
正念课程是,
Mindfulness program is,
没关系的，都很好。
it's alright, it's okay.
我认为这会帮助那些
I think it'll only help certain kids
真正对正念感兴趣的孩子。
that really is interested in it.
有些孩子来学校是因为
Some kids just come to school because
他们只是想来这里社交。
they just feel like socializing.
还有其他一些孩子,
And some of the other kids,
他们对学校和
they're more interested in school and
学校里的课程更感兴趣。
the programs that happen at the school.
奥马尔，他在学校惹了不少麻烦。
Omar, he was really getting a lot of trouble in school.
他的成绩一直是F。
He had straight Fs.
哦，他会说有一门是 D， 但对我来说，那还是全F。
Oh, he'll say one D, but to me, that's still straight Fs.
有严重的纪律问题,
Had very bad discipline problems,
有不按老师说的做的纪律问题。
a discipline problem with not doing what the teacher says.
而且还是个问题少年。
And just a problem kid.
你还好吗？
How you doing?
今天过得怎么样？
How was your day?
很好。
Good.
你的哮喘怎么样了？
How's your asthma?
没问题。
Alright.
我和我丈夫，我们认为他和我们
Me and my husband, we thought it would be best
是最好的，因为我刚刚退休了。
for him to stay with us, as I had just retired.
这里有些饼干。
There's some cookies.
有什么进展吗？
What you got, progress report?
是的。
Yeah.
他带回来一份进度报告,
He brings home a progress report,
这是他必须带回家的东西之一,
that's one of the things that he's required to bring home,
每天都要给我。
to me, everyday.
自从他去了玛丽娜学校后，每天都是这样。
And that's been every day since he's been going to Marina.
伊尔斯小姐的报告呢？
But, what about Miss Illes?
没有伊尔斯小姐的报告。
There's nothing for Miss Illes.
每天我都在向你要。
Everyday I've been asking you for.
奥马尔不听话的时候会很有挑战性。
Omar can be quite challenging when he's defiant.
很有挑战性。
Quite challenging.
我忘了。
I forget.
但这是不可接受的，对吧？
But that's not acceptable, right?
好吧。
Alright.
你什么时候才能想起来？
So when are you gonna start remembering?
我需要知道她说了什么，我知道你告诉我了什么。
I need to know what she says, I know what you tell me.
她对我有期望。
She has expectations from me.
她只是想让我在学校好好表现。
She just wants me to do good in school.
我需要你记下她对你的评价。
I need you to put down what she says about you.
她要我好好表现。
She's pushing me to do well.
有时候我不怎么听她的。
Sometimes I don't really listen to her.
我只是今天早上没做。
I just didn't do it this morning.
我觉得你应该要多做点。
I think you need to start doing more.
我不在乎,
I don't really care,
我跟她没什么好说的。
I don't have nothing to say to her.
我只是想看到你有所进步，你知道吗？
I just want to see some improvement from you, you know?
抚养奥马尔最大的好处就是
The best thing about raising Omar is
因为我已经退休了,
since I'm retired now,
我有很多时间和他在一起,
I get to spend a lot of time with him,
而之前，我在工作，努力维持生计,
whereas before, I was working, trying to make ends meet,
匆匆忙忙地吃晚饭。
rushing with dinner.
根本没时间坐下，
Just didn't have that time to sit
我真的很感激他的到来。
and really appreciate him being there.
现在，我喜欢这样。
But now, I love it.
只是陪在他身边。
Just being there for him.
他是一个优秀的人，有一颗宽广的心。
He's a great person, he has a big heart.
但是，他有很多失望的情绪不断浮现。
But, he has a lot of disappointment that keeps surfacing.
为什么？
Why?
因为我要赢。
'Cause I'm gonna win.
好吧，我们来玩骑马吧。
Alright, let's play Horse, though.
他需要学习如何
He needs to learn how to
处理那些失望或消极情绪,
handle those disappointments or negativity,
这样他就不会觉得自己输了。
so he doesn't feel like he's lost the battle.
球上一定有黄油。
Must be butter on the ball.
不是黄油,
It's no butter,
你手指上可能有黄油。
there's probably butter on your fingers.
通过练习,
With practice,
正念会对他起作用，
mindfulness would work for him
但要穿越那道愤怒的帷幕，
but it would really be hard to get through that curtain of anger,
应对它，对他来说，真得很难。
getting hold of it for him to grasp it.
我们会穿越过去的，
We're gonna get through that,
正念会有所帮助。
and mindfulness is going to help.
今天我给你们带了点东西。
Today I brought you something.
我带来的是我们可以吃的东西。
What I brought is something that we can eat.
我带来的是我们可以吃的葡萄干。
What I brought that we can eat is raisins.
好的，谁能告诉我你听到此的三种反应。
Okay, so somebody tell me your three reactions.
好吗？
Yeah?
我的第一反应是很兴奋。
My first reaction, I was excited.
第二个是,
Second one,
我想,
I was like,
好吧。
okay.
兴奋感消失了。
The excitement kinda went away.
然后你说到葡萄干。
Then you said raisins.
我不吃葡萄干。
I don't eat raisins.
我把葡萄干分给大家。
I'm gonna hand them out.
大家现在拿着，先别吃。
So just hold it right now, don't eat 'em yet.
我想让你们做的是
So what I'd like you to do is
张开你们的嘴。
open your mouth.
嘘，我们要安静地吃。
Ssh, we're gonna do this quietly.
花整整一分钟来咀嚼。
And take a whole minute to chew it.
整整一分钟？
A whole minute?
我想让你们留意的是
And what I want you to pay attention to
看看葡萄干的滋味有何变化。
is how your raisin changes.
太酸了。
It's so sour.
我们要把正念带入我们的整个体验，
We want to bring mindfulness into our entire experience,
而不仅仅是闭着眼睛坐着。
not just sitting still with our eyes closed.
正念饮食让我们有机会尝试
Mindful eating gives us a chance to experiment with
在我们每天所做的事情中更加处在当下。
being extra present in something that we do everyday.
我要你注意它的味道，感受它是如何变化的。
I want you to notice the flavor, how it changes.
其质地，是如何变化的。
The texture, how it changes.
在某种程度上，我们一天中的每一刻，
Every moment of our day includes our senses to some extent,
这是一个很好的把我们所有感官都带入这一刻的方式。
so it's a great way to bring them all together in that one moment.
但你们面临的挑战是，
But your challenge is,
下一次你在吃你喜欢的东西时，
the next time that you are eating something that you like,
我希望你留心你所吃的东西，
I want you to be mindful of it
以便你能以不同于过去的方式体验它。
so that you can experience it differently than you have in the past.
好吗？
Okay?
谢谢你们。
Thank you, you guys.
祝你们这周过得愉快。
Have a great rest of your week.
下周见。
I'll see you next week.
5.5美元。
It's $5.50.
你们准备好了吗？
You guys ready?
杰奎琳和她的朋友们正在为即将举行的才艺表演排练。
来吧。
Come on.
过来。
Come here.
我爱我的朋友们。
I love my friends.
我可以告诉他们任何事。
I can tell them anything.
这是我来学校的唯一原因,
That's the only reason why I come to school,
会见我的朋友们。
to come see my friends.
我不喜欢上课，
I don't like being in class
因为很无聊。
'cause it's boring.
我认为正念比课堂更无聊。
I think mindfulness is more boring than class.
好了，等等，停下。
Okay, wait, wait, stop.
好了，继续。
Okay, go.
一，一，二，三，一，二，三。
One, one, two, three, one, two, three.
在学校，每个人都想看到自己能飞多高走多远,
At school, everybody trying to see how far they can go,
杰奎琳也一样。
that including Jacqueline.
你们俩把那该死的椅子挪开。
Move the damn chairs, you two.
就站在那里。
Stand right there.
我不会把一切都告诉我父母。
I don't tell my parents everything.
我父母对任何事都太认真了。
Parents take everything too seriously.
如果不想在 20 岁、22 岁时挣扎，
She have to be a better person if she don't want to
她必须成为有着更好状态的人。
struggle when she gets 20, 22.
我认为这在某个时点会影响到她。
I think it's going to get into her at some point.
如果你生命中有人
Raise your hand if you have somebody in your life
和你有矛盾，但她/他却是
who you have difficulty with but it's somebody
你非常在乎或爱的人，请举手。
that you care about a lot or you love.
想想你在乎的这个人,
And bring to mind this person who you care about,
这个也许有些挑战。
but maybe there's some challenge with.
请默念：
Repeat silently,
祝你快乐。
I wish for you to be happy.
自从我父母分手后，
Ever since my parents broke up,
我真的不在乎我是否生气。
I really didn't care if I was angry or not.
我的老师和一切，好像我真的不在乎
My teachers and everything, like I really didn't care
他们是否会对我感到失望或者别的什么。
if they were frustrated with me or anything.
我祝你平安无事。
I wish for you to be safe.
杰拉尔多对我很生气。
Gerardo has a lot of anger towards me.
我觉得我们和大家一样有起有落。
I think we have up and downs like everybody.
有时候我们相处得很好，我们在一起很开心,
Sometimes we get along good, we have fun together,
我们一起共度时光。
we spend time together.
而有时候我们就是合不来。
And sometimes we just don't get along.
有时候我觉得是因为我没和他爸爸住在一起，
Sometimes I think it's because I'm not living with his dad
他很难理解
and it's hard for him to understand
我们不再在一起了。
that we're not together anymore.
每个人找一个与这个人有关的
Find a wish on your own that's meaningful
有意义的愿望，然后你们来许愿。
regarding this person, and you make the wish.
你们选个愿望。
You choose the wish.
有时候妈妈会对我大喊大叫。
Sometimes mom, she yells at me.
整个地方就像
The whole place just feels all
一锅正在煮的水，你知道吗？
like a pot of water that's cooking, you know?
气氛非常紧张。
It's all heated.
有时候你可以逃避,
Sometimes you can run away form it,
而有时候你真的做不到。
sometimes you really can't.
有时候，你必须在那里,
Sometimes you just gotta like, be there,
然后你就会被灼伤。
and you gotta burn, the little pot thing.
把注意力停留在你的身体上,
Let your attention rest in your body,
注意你的身体和头脑的感受。
just noticing how your body feels and how your mind feels.
我想让杰拉尔多毕业，拿到学位。
I want Gerardo to graduate, have a degree.
我知道他能做到,
I know that he can do it,
但现在时机不对，
but right now it's tough timing,
对他来说在学校集中注意力真的很难。
it's really hard for him to focus in school.
但我希望他能在生活中出人头地。
But I want him to be somebody in life.
太棒了,
That was great,
但我真的很好奇是否有人
but I'm really curious if anyone is
愿意分享刚才做的时候的感觉。
willing to share what that was like.
房间里感觉很静，
The room felt still,
但当我看着每个学生时，
but when I looked at each individual student,
我不知道他们内在发生了什么，
I didn't know what was going on for them
他们并没有真正地主动交流与分享。
and they're not being really forthcoming and sharing.
如果有人认为正念很有帮助，
Can I have a show of hands
或者你从中学到了什么，
if anybody thought that it was helpful
或者你意识到了什么，
or that you learned something,
请举手示意。
or you realized something?
到最后，我希望他们确实有一个工具，
By the end, hopefully they do have a tool that they can
可以在需要的时候依赖或利用。
depend on or draw upon in moments of need.
今天早上我用了正念，因为妈妈,
This morning I used mindfulness 'cause mom,
她对我大喊大叫，因为我早上没起床。
she was yelling at me 'cause I didn't get up in the morning.
我当时很生气。
And I was just mad.
我只想锁上门，然后想,
I was just gonna lock the door and like,
回去睡觉，今天不去上学了。
go back to sleep and not go to school today.
但之后我冷静了一下，
But then I, I just chilled for a little bit,
很快就用了正念，这让我感觉更平静。
I used mindfulness real quick and it made me feel more calm.
这也让我清醒过来。
It kind of woke me up, too.
后来我去上学了。
And I came to school.
♪ 我会找到你
♪ Gonna find you
♪慢慢来
♪ And take it slowly
♪ 准备好了吗，我来了
♪ Ready or not, here I come
♪ 你躲不掉
♪ You can't hide
早上好。
Good morning.
所以，这次我想尝试的是,
So, what I want to try this time,
在你做正念呼吸的时候,
is while you're doing mindful breathing,
我会故意发出一点点噪音。
I'm gonna deliberately gonna make a little bit of noise.
使用锚词“吸气”和“呼气”
And using the anchor words breathing in and breathing out
将帮助你保持专注于呼吸，
will help you stay focused on your breathing
即使有一些分心或混乱的情况。
even when there's some distraction or chaos.
吸气，呼气。
Breathing in, breathing out.
在开始的时候，我并不惊讶，当事情变得安静时，
I wasn't surprised in the beginning when things got quiet
人们会发出放屁的声音之类的。
people would like, make fart noises and stuff.
但之后,
But later on,
大概一个月后,
like maybe like a month later,
事情就好起来了。
things got better.
当她敲响钵声时，周围一片寂静。
Things were actually silent when she rang the bell.
现在当她敲钵时，我们可能会
And now when she rings the bell, we could be like,
大喊大叫，争吵不休，但我们仍然知道
yelling and stuff, and fighting, but we still know
当钵声一响,
when that bell rings,
我们就会停下来。
that we stop.
到法院去吧，亚历克斯。
Go by the court, Alex.
我没有和我的朋友谈论过正念。
I haven't talked about mindfulness with my friends.
我和家人谈过了。
I talked about it with my family.
我有一个哥哥。
I have one brother.
我本来还有个哥哥，但他死了。
I woulda had another brother, but he died.
我从他那里学会了如何打篮球。
I learned how to play basketball from him.
我哥哥二十二岁。
My brother was twenty two.
伙计，他说他会来吗？
So dude, he said he gonna come?
不，他要我们去接他。
No, he want us to come and get him.
他会和我们一起去音乐会吗？
Is he gonna come to concert with us?
哥哥死后，他在学校发生了变化，
After his brother died, he changed in school,
他的成绩下降了。
his grades went down.
他的行为有点冷漠,
His behavior was kind of nonchalant,
好像他什么都不在乎似的。
like he didn't really care about too much anything.
等他长大一点,
And when he got a little older,
就开始想找麻烦什么的了，对吧？
that's when you start trying to get in trouble and stuff, huh?
是的。
Yeah.
这是我哥哥。
This is my brother.
死于五年前。
He died five years ago.
我问了很多人是否知道是谁干的。
I was asking a lot of people if they knew who did it.
知道了吗？
Did you?
是的。
Yeah.
有些人知道是谁干的，有些人拒不回答。
Some people said yes, some people said no.
不过我也无能为力。
Not like I could do something about it, though.
是的。
Yeah.
在他死后，然后其他几个
After he died, then a couple other people that you
你认识和爱的人也死了，就这样,
knew and loved, died too, and so it was,
你就开始真的发泄了。
you start really acting out.
这是我另一个朋友，吉恩。
This is my other friend, Gene.
他颈后中枪，
This is the one that got shot in the back of the neck
一路跑到他奶奶家，
and ran all the way to his granny house
死在了她的地板上。
and died on her floor.
那是在新学年开始的时候。
That was in the beginning of the school year.
你想他吗？
You miss him?
是的。
Yeah.
我也是。
I do, too.
我们小时候经常去那里玩。
We used to play over there when we were little.
那边是什么？
What was over there?
就是空地。
Just open field.
它大吗？
Was it bigger?
那棵树阴森森的。
And the tree was so shady.
他是不是就在门口被杀的？
Did he get killed like right there at the gate?
有人走过来向他开枪。
And somebody had came up and shot him.
见过了太多的死亡，然后你就会变得很沮丧,
Too much death and you get too depressed,
有时候这里就像战区一样。
it's almost like a war zone sometimes out here.
维尼曾经在那里吹过气球吗？
Vinnie used to heckle balloons over there?
是的，气球，泰迪熊。
Yeah, balloons, teddy bears.
然后发生了什么？
Then what happened?
他们把这个门竖起来了，因为一开始这个门不在那里。
They put this gate up because at first the gate wasn't there.
我正尽可能把精力放在学校和体育上，
I'm trying to focus on school and sports,
基本上就是这样。
that's basically it.
希望如果我继续运动,
And hopefully if I keep on playing sports,
也许能让我离开这里。
that could probably get me out of here.
我可以带着我的家人离开里士满。
I could take my family out of Richmond.
我们会搬到别的地方。
We'd just move somewhere.
是的，他们在这里长大，
Yeah, they grew up right here
就像我在这个街区长大一样。
just like I grew up on this block.
他们都死了。
They all dead.
今天我能找个人来带领吗？
Alright, can I get somebody to lead today?
你想试试吗，奥马尔？
Do you want to, Omar?
奥马尔今天也参加了。
Omar was participating today.
我是说，他参与的方式
I mean, he participates in a way that's also
也是在制造点小麻烦。
making a little bit of trouble.
他有自己的角色，
He has a certain role
他下了点决心要扮演这个角色并参与进来。
and he's kind of determined to play the role and participate.
他似乎正在努力做到这一点。
And he seems to be managing that.
非常优雅。
Just very elegant.
等等，你想说什么？
So hold on, what do you want to say?
保持一个专注的姿势。
Get in a mindful posture.
乌木。
Ebony.
起来。
Get up.
哦，你说的时候得友善点。
Oh, you have to be kind, though.
好好说。
Say it in a nice way.
乌木，你能坐起身来吗？
Ebony, can you please sit up?
谢谢你。
Thank you.
现在往下看，听听钵声，好吗？
Now look down, and listen to the bell, okay?
闭上眼睛。
Keep your eyes closed.
你现在感觉怎么样？
How do you feel right now?
放松了。
Relaxed.
放松了？
Relaxed?
还有别的感觉吗？
Anything else?
我认为奥马尔已经
I think Omar's reaching a point
达到了认真对待正念的地步。
where he's taking mindfulness seriously.
你喜欢在一群人面前吗？
Do you like being in front of a group?
是的，没关系。
Yeah, it's alright.
这很酷。
It's cool.
他真的很善于反思，
He's really reflective,
他会思考发生的事情，
he thinks about what happens,
他能看清事情两方面的情况。
he's able to look at both sides.
好的。
Alright.
来吧，敲吧。
Go ahead, ring it.
正念确实有点让我吃惊。
Mindfulness kind of did surprise me.
我以为我永远不会用到它，但我用了。
I didn't think I was ever gonna use it but I did.
请注意你现在的感觉。
Please notice how you're feeling right now.
我们在外面的院子里，
We were outside in the yard,
有个女孩让我很生气。
and then some girl just made me mad.
她会像鲁比一样揍你。
She will beat your ass like Ruby.
我就觉得要把她的头发
I just felt like pulling her hair out
扯下来掉到地上，然后掐死她。
dropping to the floor and choke her.
我用正念让自己平静下来，什么也不做。
And I used mindfulness to calm down and not do nothing.
我高兴做了正念，因为若这样做会有不良后果的。
I like it, 'cause there's consequences for that.
我感觉挺高兴的，因为我可以真正地进行思考，
I kind of feel happy 'cause I get to really think about things
不犯以后会后悔的错误。
and not make a mistake that I will regret doing later on.
让开。
Move over.
当我对学校里的其他孩子生气时,
When I get angry at other kids at school,
我真的很擅长给他们难堪。
I'm really good at putting them at their spot.
老色鬼。
Dirty old goat.
哦，她没听见。
Oh, she didn't hear.
我看到了杰奎琳可爱的一面,
I've seen the sweet side of Jacqueline,
有时候我希望她能表现出来，但是
and I sometimes would like her to show it, but
我猜她不想让任何人看到这一面。
I guess she doesn't really want anyone to see it.
你想推我吗？
You trying to push me?
如果我要为别人看到的杰奎琳
So if I was gonna write down words for the Jackie
写下一些文字，我会想出什么词来呢？
that other people see, what words would I come up with?
很好。
Nice.
嗯哼。
Mm hmm.
有意思。
Funny.
嗯哼。
Mm hmm.
他们看我的眼神好像我很刻薄。
They look at me like I'm mean.
有时候他们觉得你刻薄？
Sometimes they see you as mean?
是的。
Yes.
那太可怕了。
That's awful.
杰奎琳喜欢参与正念。
Jacqueline likes participating in mindfulness.
我觉得她的参与度发生了变化。
I think that her engagement has shifted.
你可以两者兼备，不是很有趣吗？
Isn't it interesting that you can be both?
我希望她能开始对
I'm hoping that she starts to gain some perspective
最近发生的与其她女孩的交往
on these incidents that are happening recently with
并与她们争吵打架之类的事情有一些新的认识，
other girls and getting into fights and all this stuff
并能为自己选择一条不同的道路。
and choose a different path for herself.
内心的杰希长什么样？
What's the Jackie on the inside?
害羞。
Shy.
我不认为正念会改变我。
I don't think doing mindfulness changes me at all.
你觉得有人知道你害羞吗？
Do you think anybody knows you're shy?
没人。
No.
你觉得正念怎样？
What about thoughtful?
不咋样。
No.
很无聊，就像,
It's boring, but like,
如果我生气之类的，可以拿它作为一种工具。
I could use it as a tool if I'm mad or something.
当人们觉得你刻薄的时候,
When people see you as mean,
你觉得这是怎么回事？
what's that all about?
因为我把他们推来推去，
'Cause I push them around and like
我会打他们。
I hit them and stuff like that.
所以你表现得很强硬。
So you kind of act tough.
你就是这样的人吗？
Is that who you are?
这就是你内心的一部分吗？
That is a little bit of who you are on the inside?
好吧，我们先把它放一边。
Okay, let's put that there.
你能坦诚相待真是太好了。
That's really good for you to be honest about that.
内心也有点刻薄。
A little mean on the inside, too.
是的。
Yeah.
你能接受这一点吗？
You okay with that?
是的。
Okay.
你觉得这是从哪儿来的？
Where do you think that comes from?
我不知道。
I don't know.
她确实在使用正念，
She does use mindfulness,
我不知道她为什么不说，但她确实在用正念。
I don't know why she doesn't say it, but she does.
她会遇到麻烦，我会帮她解决,
She would have problems and I would help her out,
但有时候她会用正念帮助自己。
but sometimes she would just use mindfulness to help herself.
你的电池快没电了。
Your battery is fucking low.
早上好。
Good morning.
大家能把椅子转向前面吗？
Can I get everybody to turn your chairs towards the front?
再敲一次，引起他们的注意。
Ring it again to get their attention.
早上好。
Good morning.
自从我上周三见到你之后，如果你们记得使用正念，
Can you raise your hand if you remembered to use mindfulness
请举个手。
since I saw you on Wednesday?
好的，很多人都记得。
Okay, that's a lot.
如果你愿意说你什么时候用过，
Can you keep your hand up
可以举起你们的手。
if you're willing to say when you used it?
杰奎琳。
Jacqueline.
星期四。
Thursday.
因为出了点状况。
'Cause there was a problem.
你用了什么正念形式？
And what kind of mindfulness did you use?
正念呼吸。
Breathing.
你为什么决定用正念呼吸？
And why did you decide to use breathing?
因为她让我冷静下来。
'Cause she told me to calm down.
莱斯利和你在一起，
So Lesly was with you
她让你冷静下来吗？
and she told you to calm down?
嗯哼。
Mm hmm.
有用吗? 有帮助吗? 有什么改变吗？
And did it work or help or change anything?
嗯哼。
Mm hmm.
你还有什么要说的吗？
Will you say anything more about it?
没什么要说的了。
There's nothing else to say.
好的。
Okay.
我知道，好的。
I know, alright.
当我在学校遇到问题时，
When I have problems at school,
我根本不和我的父母说话，
I really don't talk to my parents,
真的不和我妈妈说话。
not really my mom.
我不觉得她能理解我。
I don't really feel like she can understand me.
我爱我的父母，我很高兴有他们两个人。
I love my parents. I'm happy to have both of them.
我是家里唯一的姐姐，唯一的女儿。
I am the only sister, the only daughter.
和我的两个小弟弟在一起，我感到很孤独。
I feel lonely with the two little brothers I have.
有时候我会生他们的气。
Sometimes I get mad at them.
别往那边扔了。
Stop throwing it over there.
我处理生气的方式就是，
The way I deal with getting mad is that I would just
假装什么都没发生，把它藏在心里,
pretend nothing happens and keep it in me,
永远不让任何人知道。
never let anybody know.
在学校也一样。
Same thing at school.
有人让我哭泣，没有人知道这一点,
Someone makes me cry and no one else knew about it,
我会把它藏在心里，假装什么都没发生。
I would keep it to myself and pretend nothing happened.
我真的没办法发泄出来。
I really have no way to let it out.
我去的地方总是很吵。
It's always, like, loud everywhere I go.
永远没有安静过。
It's never quiet.
从来没有静过。
Never still.
我们冥想的时候，总是很安静，
When we meditate it's always quiet
我可以听到不同的声音，
and I get to listen to different sounds
这对我来说真的很不一样。
and it's really different for me.
我的家人对此很感兴趣，并且想要了解
My family would get interest and want to learn about
正念课程以及我从中学到的东西。
the mindfulness class and what I've learned from it.
要有耐心是很难的。
It's difficult to be patient.
我明白如果她继续参加这个放松计划，
I understand that if she continues with this relaxation program
会更平静，也会让周遭环境放松些。
it will be calmer and relax this environment a bit.
我喜欢她参加这个项目。
I like that she's taking this program.
这样我们就能从她身上学到一些东西。
So that we can learn something about it through her.
我第二节课有美术课。
I have art class for second period.
我喜欢画画，比如，我想画一些有关
I like to draw, like, if I want to draw something about
旧金山的画作，我喜欢画建筑之类的东西。
San Francisco, I like draw the buildings and stuff.
我也喜欢涂鸦艺术。
I like graffiti arts, too.
一，二...
And one, two...
不喜欢画苹果或之类的东西。
Not like drawing apples or nothing like that.
我不喜欢那些东西。
I don't really like that.
我到处画画是为了让自己在某种程度上更有才华。
I draw everywhere to make myself more talented in a way.
通过涂鸦，我可以看到愤怒的情绪消失了，
With doing graffiti, I can see that the anger goes away
他会要求有独处的时间作画。
and he will ask for time alone to do that.
如果我练习,
If I practice,
我可以像这里的人一样成为一名画家。
I could be a painter like people here.
我和其他人一样有天赋，
I could have as much talent as anybody
我只需要坚持下去。
but I just need to keep at it.
我画画的时候实际上不需要用到正念,
I don't really need to use mindfulness when I draw,
但它给了我一点动力，正念会帮助我
but like, it gives me a little boost to try to help me
集中注意力，看看我到底想画什么。
concentrate and try to see what I wanna draw.
等我长大了，如果我可以把画画当副业,
When I grow up, if I can paint or draw as a side job,
那就太酷了。
then that would be cool.
如果我能把它做成一份可靠的工作,
And if I could do it as a solid, solid job,
那么我会，是的，我肯定会这么做。
then I would, yeah, I would definitely do that.
这样很好。
This is nice.
我想，我确实有可能在七年级挂科。
I think it's true that I'm in danger of failing seventh grade.
这并不意味着我就会放弃。
It doesn't mean that I'm gonna just quit.
这意味着我要更努力通过测验。
It means that I'm gonna try harder to pass.
埃恩勒先生，
Mister Ehnle,
我想知道你们班有没有在我不在场时
I wanted to know if you as a class have ever done
做过正念练习？
mindfulness without me?
做过。
Yes.
没有。
No.
我们没有做。
We have not.
好的,
Okay,
我想知道你们有没有钵？
I wondered if you had a bell?
最能持续正念的班级,
The classes that best sustain mindfulness,
老师和学生即使在正念课程结束后
the teachers and the students continue to use the bell
也会继续使用钵，
even when the program is finished,
这样在教室里就有了个固定的工具，
so that there's this constant tool in the classroom
它会给正念练习一个提醒，
to give a reminder of mindfulness and
引导大家进行正念练习。
to facilitate a mindful practice.
为了让同学们平静下来，重新集中注意力,
In terms of calming things down, refocusing,
正念是值得在课堂上花时间学习的。
mindfulness was worth the class time.
这一点毋庸置疑。
No doubt about that.
正念让学生们觉得
It makes them feel
自己对自己和自己的行为
like thy have more control over themselves
有更多的掌控权，而不是
and their behavior and that they aren't simply
外部环境的受害者。
victims of external circumstances.
现在我们来看看数学。
So, now we're going to look at some math.
圆的面积等于
The volume of a circle,
π 乘以半径的平方。
Pi times radius squared.
在练习正念之前，我有点像,
Before mindfulness, I would just be like,
不知道该做什么，不注意任何事情。
not knowing what to do, not paying attention to anything.
而现在，当我需要坐下来工作时，
And like now, when I need to sit down and do my work,
我只是想一下，然后对自己说，你必须这么做。
I just think about it and like, say, you gotta do this, you know?
这是什么词？
What word is this?
Though.
我觉得他们对自己的所作所为感觉好多了。
I think they feel better about what they're doing.
他们更有自信。
They have more self-confidence.
他们注意力更集中了。
They're paying attention better.
他们觉得自己上课更专注了。
That they feel more engaged in the lessons.
好的，非常好。
Okay, very good.
我的性格变了。
My personality changed.
因为如果想之前一样有冲突,
'Cause if there was a conflict before,
我可能已经准备好要吵架了。
I would probably be ready to fight.
但现在我会更多地对自己说，放松、冷静。
But now I'm just like, more, laid back, calm.
我们取一条对称线。
We take a line of symmetry and then.
教师的角色已经扩大了。
The role of the teacher has expanded.
我们面临的最大挑战是
The biggest challenge that we have is
改变这些学校建筑内的系统和结构，
changing our systems and structures within these
这样孩子们才能融入学校。
school buildings so the kids can fit in.
如果你去看看帮助学生
If you go and look at database indicators
学习的数据库指标，
that help students learn,
自我反省的行为在这个名单上排名靠前,
self-reflective behavior is way up on that list,
这也是我们很多优秀的学习者
and that's one of the things that many of our good learners
会带到学校而其他人没有带来的东西。
bring that others don't bring to the school.
因此，像这样一个帮助教导孩子们的项目，
And so a program like this that helps teach kids that,
并帮助它成为学校实践的一部分，
and helps it become a part of the practice within the school
强化这一点的话，将帮助到这些孩子们。
and reinforces that is going to help them.
整幅壁画,
The whole mural,
是关于我们如何在城市中有更多的和平。
it's about how we need more peace in the city.
制作这件作品最棒的环节
The best part of making this piece
是和其他人一起工作。
was working with other people.
我觉得正念教会了我如何冷静下来,
I think mindfulness taught me how to calm down,
尽量不把问题挡在事情的发展道路上，
to try to not put problems in the way of stuff
而真正选择我想要的想法，
and choose what I want to think
选择我想要的感觉。
and choose how I want to feel.
我可以在上涂抹吗？
Should I paint over it?
好啊，再涂一层白色？
Yeah, and then maybe a layer of white?
好的，我知道，在它上面涂抹。
Yeah, I know, paint over it.
其他老师告诉我，他做不成事,
The other teachers that tell me he can't do good,
他只会捣乱，你知道吗？
all he does is disrupt, you know?
最后有人说，
It's like finally somebody's saying
他们对我的工作印象深刻，
that they're impressed on what I do
他们很高兴我在那里作画。
and that they're happy that I'm there.
这让我感觉很好，
It makes me feel good,
让我觉得，我知道我可以好好作画。
makes me feel like I know I could do it.
好了，今天是我们正念课程的最后一天。
Okay, so today is our last day of mindfulness.
不！
No!
马特？
Matt?
如果你们有什么反应或者想说什么,
So, if you have a reaction, or something to say,
我希望你们只去注意到自己的反应。
I want you to just notice it in yourself.
如果你们无法控制自己的冲动,
If you can not control your impulse,
你们得问问自己，是谁在控制？
you have to ask yourself, who's in control?
我想请你们闭上眼睛或低下头。
I'm gonna ask you to keep your eyes closed or down.
我想让你注意到移动眼睛，
So I want you to notice the impulse to move your eyes
或移动身体，或想说话的冲动。
or move your body or talk.
真正尝试容纳这种冲动，以便你能控制，
And really try to contain that so that you are in control,
不是...东西
not something...
正念并不能使问题消失。
Mindfulness doesn't make problems go away.
认为如果你长期练习，那么你就不会再生气，
It's a wrong assumption to think that if you
或者你就不会再有问题，或者没有人会对你生气，
practice for a long time, then you'll never be angry again,
或者你再也不会有麻烦了，
or you'll never have another problem
或者没人会对你生气。
or no one will ever be mad at you.
这根本不是重点,
That's not the point at all,
你永远无法创造这种情况。
and you can never create that situation.
关键是你满足你经历的方式发生了变化，
It's that the way you're meeting your experience changes
允许更多的轻松和更多的幸福来满足情况。
to allow more lightness and more happiness to meet situations.
只关注你自己,
Just focusing on yourself,
并尊重你周围的人,
and respecting the people around you,
我们将听到钵声。
and we'll listen to the sound of the bell.
注意到让你分心的东西,
Noticing what distracts you,
如果你能集中注意力两分钟。
and if you can stay focused for two minutes.
我不知道为什么我这么容易分心。
I don't know why I get distracted really easily.
有时我也会偷懒。
Sometimes I get lazy.
我必须坐在远离朋友的地方，
I'm gonna have to sit away from my friends
控制自己，做好自己的工作，不偷懒。
and control myself, do my work and not get lazy.
我今天给你们带了点东西。
I did bring something for you today.
马特，你想说点什么吗？
Matt, do you want to say something?
是的。
Yes.
好的。
Okay.
是葡萄干吗？
Is it raisins?
不是。
No.
是葡萄干麦麸吗？
Is it raisin bran?
不是。
No.
我将在以后使用正念。
I will use mindfulness in the future.
我现在觉得这是理所当然的。
I think I kind of take it for granted now.
梅根来了，
Megan comes in
像对我们说，你们可以放松一下。
and it's like, you get to relax.
往后,
Later on,
也许一两年后,
maybe a year from now or two,
我想我会更多地使用正念。
I think I'll use mindfulness more.
这叫袖珍心形。
They're called pocket hearts.
无论你看到它，感觉到它，还是记得它,
Whenever you see it or feel it or remember it,
我希望它是个能提醒你的东西，
I want it to be something that reminds you that
你现在有一个工具，你可以在往后余生使用正念。
you have a tool now that you can use for the rest of your life.
看到我爸的工作方式，我感觉他压力很大。
Seeing how my dad works, like, it's stressful.
如果我有压力的话，我会用正念的。
I think I would want to use it if I was stressed.
正念就像你背包里的东西,
It's like something in your backpack,
它一直都在那里，你可以把它拿出来，然后使用它。
it's always there and you can just pull it out and use it.
一旦你有了这个袖珍心形,
Once you have your heart,
我想让你至少想
I want you to think about
一件你学到了的东西。
at least one thing that you've learned.
我被坐在我旁边的许多人分散了注意力。
I get distracted by many people who are sitting beside me.
他们会开始取笑我，
They're gonna start teasing me
并对我不断进行骚扰。
and bothering me about everything.
我只是喜欢去一个私人的地方，
I just like going to a private place and
说出我内心所有的想法，我的感受。
saying all my thoughts inside of me, what I feel.
没人能看到我做的任何事。
Nobody is there to look and see anything that I do.
有人能说说如果每个人
Can anybody say how school would be different
都练习正念，学校会有什么不同吗？
if everybody practiced mindfulness?
谁来说说？
Yeah?
没有欺凌。
No bullying.
没有欺凌，是的。
No bullying, yeah.
你为什么认为这样就不会发生欺凌事件呢？
Why do you think that would make no bullying happen?
因为很多人都受到了
Because many people have been getting hurt
别人的伤害。
by people picking on them.
好的，谢谢。
Yeah, thank you.
如果全世界都用正念，
It'll make a difference
整个世界都会大变样。
if the whole world used mindfulness.
很多人就不会被杀了。
A lot of people wouldn't be killed.
射击会减少。
It would be less shooting.
好了，各位，祝你们暑假快乐。
Alright everybody, I wish you a happy summer.
明年我可能见不到你们，祝大家八年级快乐。
And if I don't see you next year, happy eighth grade.
保重，谢谢。
Take care, thank you.
奥马尔、莱斯利、杰奎琳
和赫拉多都在年底获得升学。
他们的违纪转介次数都大幅下降。
他们的老师、家长和孩子们都觉得
对自己的行为有了更多的控制。
♪ 有时我躺在月光下
♪ Sometimes I lay under the moon
♪ 感谢上天我在呼吸着
♪ I thank God I'm breathing
♪ 我祈祷不要带走我
♪ Then I pray don't take me soon
♪ 因为我在此地有个缘由
♪ 'Cause I am here for a reason
♪ 有时我会泪流满面
♪ Sometimes in my tears I drown
奥马尔仍然在学业上挣扎。
但他已经毕业并在上高中。
他的家人和老师说，
他现在有了更多的平静，愤怒少了。
♪ 但我从不让它给我带来失望
♪ But I never let it get me down
♪当消极情绪笼罩时
♪ So when negativity surrounds
♪ 我知道有一天一切都会好起来，
♪ I know someday it will all turn around
莱斯利说，正念帮助她
克服了困难的社交和家庭问题。
她现在在旧金山的高中就读。
♪ 因为我一生都在等待
♪ because all my life I been waiting for
♪ 我一直在祈祷
♪ I been praying for
♪ 人们会说
♪ For the people to say
♪ 我们不想再打仗了
♪ That we don't wanna fight no more
♪ 不会再有战争了
♪ There'll be no more war
杰奎琳的妈妈说，
正念帮助她变得更平静、
更尊重他人并提高了她的成绩。
♪我们的孩子将玩起来
♪ And our children will play
杰拉尔多获得了 8 年级
最大 GPA 增益特别奖，
并因指导年轻学生而受到表彰。
他的父亲说这种变化是“惊人的”。
♪ 这不是零和游戏
♪ It's not about win or lose
♪因为我们都会失去
♪ 'Cause we all lose when they feed on the
♪ 无辜的灵魂
♪ Souls of the innocent
凌布什希望有一天
能有足够的钱为玛丽娜中学的
所有学生带来正念课程。
♪ 鲜血淋漓的人行道
♪ Blood drenched pavement
♪ 继续前行，尽管水流汹涌
♪ Keep on moving though the waters stay raging
♪在这迷宫里，你会迷失方向
♪ In this maze you can lose your way
正念课程结束后对七年级学生的调查发现：
80%的学生在心烦意乱时更容易平静下来
58%的学生在课堂上更专注
40%的学生用正念来避免争吵或打架
34%的学生说正念提高了他们的成绩
86%的学生说更多的小孩应该学正念
♪也许会让你疯狂，但别让它影响你
♪ It might drive you crazy but don't let it phase you
♪ 绝不可能
♪ No way
♪ 有时我会泪流满面
♪ Sometimes in my tears I drown
♪ 但我从不让它给我带来失望
♪ But I never let it get me down
♪所以当消极情绪笼罩
♪ So when negativity surrounds
♪我知道有一天一切都会好起来
♪ I know someday it'll all turn around
在对其他八所学校学习正念的
近 1,000 名学生进行的一项调查中
也发现了类似的结果。
♪ 因为我的一生一直在等待
♪ because all my life I been waiting for
♪我一直在祈祷
♪ I been praying for
♪ 人们在说
♪ For the people to say
♪ 我们不想再打仗
♪ That we don't wanna fight no more
自 1970 年代以来，
世界各地学校的数百万学生
学习了正念和其他基于冥想的技巧。
这些面向 K-12 学生的计划正在继续快速增长中。
♪ 不会再有战争
♪ There'll be no more war
♪我们的孩子将玩起来
♪ And our children will play ♪
♪ 有一天这一切都会改变
♪ One this all will change
♪ 一视同仁
♪ Treat people the same
♪ 停止暴力
♪ Stop with the violence
♪ 停止仇恨
♪ Stop with the hate
♪总有一天，我们会自由自在
♪ One day we'll all be free and proud to be
♪在同一片阳光下，唱着自由之歌
♪ Under the same sun singing songs of freedom like